Dhanapal Jayapandi

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING MANAGER · SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

11675 Rainwater Dr, Alpharetta, GA 30009

□ (+1) 678-666-0066 | **□** itsdhana@gmail.com | **☆** djay93.github.io | **□** djay93

Summary _

Software engineering manager, architect and development expert with 10+ years of professional experience. Solid track record in designing and implementing elegant and pragmatic solutions for enterprise applications. History of excellence in digital transformation, cloud, data engineering, architecture and technical leadership. Growth mindset kept by seeking new challenges and learning new skills, languages, and tools. Aim to utilize my analytical and technical skills to impact core business strategy and results of a growing higher performance organization.

Work Experience _____

Amdocs Inc. Atlanta, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING MANAGER

Oct 2011 - Present

- Managed large-scale Enterprise applications in production enivronments: Mobility CRM (30K users/800K calls per day), Uverse CRM (20K users/400K calls per day), Business eBill (2M users/10B bills per month) and MDE (2M campaigns per day).
- Designed and developed digital bill payment and presentment microservice APIs, resulting in a 100% availability for the online billing portal.
- Implemented automated deployment pipelines for microservices running as Docker containers using Jenkins, Ansible and Maven.
- Overhauled web applications from server-side rendering view technologies (JSP/Struts) to client-side rendering view technologies (Angular), leading to increased usability and 100% mobile responsiveness.
- Conceptualized, redesigned and optimized ETL processor to extract invoices data from billing data feed into Oracle/Cassandra datastore.
- · Spearheaded development of Mass data load system, MDE, to help Business with mass campaigns, adjustments and BOGO offers.
- Revamped MDE to reduce system coupling; directed parallelized algorithms to improved the performance by 500%.
- · Managed product deliverables, project deadlines, system availability, technology infrastructure, system security and business proposals.
- Promoted Agile transformation efforts to improve team velocity by 2x times instituted retrospectives, continuous integration, code reviews and automated testing.
- Administred proof of concept efforts to help with pre-sales and new technology standards.
- · Led a team of software engineers to design and implement software projects, generating over \$2MM+ in annual revenue.
- · Identified security risks, performance issues and technical debts, and recommended changes to simplify the on-going maintenance.

Amdocs Inc. St. Louis, USA

DEVELOPMENT EXPERT Oct 2009 - Sep 2011

- Designed and developed an intuitive and easy-to-use Dispute and Adjustment module for an estimated 50% efficiency gain in operations and potential net savings of \$400K for AT&T.
- Formulated implementation and ongoing maintenance plan for Enterprise CRM applications; managed overall service infrastructure focusing on high-availability, business continuity and system performance.
- Contributed to CRM software, through design discussions, code reviews, and commits; implemented 200+ commits (18k LOC) in 12 months.
- Managed and mentored junior software developers; helped with knowledge on best practices and techniques of software development and CRM implementation.
- Promoted to Software engineering manager within 24 months due to strong performance and organizational impact ahead of schedule by 24 months.

Amdocs Development Ltd

Limassol, Cyprus

SENIOR SUBJECT MATTER EXPERT

Jul 2006 - Oct 2009

- · Involved in the development and maintenance of Amdocs CRM implementations AT&T Mobility, AT&T Uverse, Excelcom, Telstra and Isabella.
- · Analyzed new features from customers and proposed both business and technology solution to implement in the existing application.
- Upgraded the CRM from v12.5 to v6.0 suite and v6 to v7.5 Amdocs suite for Cingular/AT&T Mobility.
- Implemented Amdocs CRM v7.5 for Isabella, Kazakhstan government to manage e-service tickets.
- Authored proof-of-concept to show business value of Amdocs CRM to DishNET, Telstra and Excelcom.
- Provided bug fixes, performance fixes, query optimizations and usability improvements.

Amdocs Development Ltd

Limassol, Cyprus

SUBJECT MATTER EXPERT Oct 2004 - Jun 2006

- Designed, developed and deployed large-scale CRM for TOnline and VFUK.
- Implemented a logging framework for TOnline backend applications to logs messages in Eclipse Common Base Event (CBE) format.
- · Analyzed and fixed performance issues and functional defects in existing CRM implementations.
- Provided bug fixes for Amdocs eCare Integration APIs, Orion release.
- Involved in the testing of Orion and Omega releases of Amdocs CRM.

HCL Technologies Chennai, India

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jun 2003 - Oct 2004

- Developed DART, Developers Automated Regression Tool, for testing pricing, usage and billing APIs of Convergys Atlys Billing System.
- Enhanced the digital knowledge base of Atlys Billing with latest technologies.

Key Skills ___

Languages Java, JavaScript (ES5/ES6), C++, Python, Ruby, PHP, Perl, Unix Shells, AWK

Backend Spring, SpringBoot, Node.js, Express, Rails, Laravel **Frontend** Angular, React.js, Vue.js, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Sass

Databases Oracle, MySQL, Cassandra, MongoDB, Redis

Cloud & Containers Kubernetes, AWS (EKS, Lambda, EC2, IAM, S3), Azure, Serverless Framework

CI/CD Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible, Git, Gitlab, Jenkins, Gradle, Maven

Systems Red Hat Linux 5/6/7, Sun Solaris, IBM AIX, Weblogic, Apache Tomcat EE, Nginx

Domain Knowledge CRM, ETL, BI & Analytics, Order management, Electronic bill payments, Self-service portals, Campaigns

Others Nagios, Vagrant

Certifications

2019 **SAFe Agilist**, Scaled Agile Framework

2013 Project Management Professional (PMP), PMI

2008 **Sun Certified Java Developer**, J2SE 5.0

2006 Sun Certified Web Component Developer, J2EE 1.4

2005 **Sun Certified Java Programmer**, J2SE 5.0

Education

College of Engineering (Anna University)

Guindy, India

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Jun. 1999 - May. 2003

• Got Gupta Scholarship which is given to promising students in CSE Dept.